Food
Hello friends can you hear me
?  I am Yogendra Verma, Health Insurance
Expert.  Today I have brought for you an amazing and very
good working plan named
Critical Illness Plan ICC Lombard
's Critical Shield Plus Plan.  This is an amazing
and great plan, friends.
This plan covering 92 types of critical issues is
amazing and powerful in itself.
Today I am going to tell and explain this to you.  It
is requested to all of you that it is
important to watch this live carefully till the end.   Only then will
you understand everything well.
This is the first plan which
covers 92 major and minor critical illnesses.
Whenever a 100% major illness occurs in the family,
100% claim will be given and if any
minor illness occurs, the company provides claim on 25% of the minor illness.
Five types of major critical illnesses are covered here.
And minor
critical issues are also covered within it.
What is that from the five majors?  Cancer and blood
disorders.  Number two heart and blood
vessels.  Number Three Major Organs.  Number
three.  Number four nervous systems.  Number five
other illnesses.  These are the five main
critical incidents that will be covered for you.  There
is no survival waiting period of any kind in this.  This is a very
amazing and tremendous thing.  And the
best thing is that there is an initial
waiting period of 90 days.  Whenever you
take a critical illness plan, you have to keep this in
mind.  Enhanced coverage with multi-
claim options.  Even if you get a
major illness claim in one of your capacities,
your policy will continue for the remaining four things.
This option is also great.  There
is optional coverage here for 106 surgical procedures in
which if there is a major illness and surgery is
required then 100% claim will be given and if there is a
minor surgery then 50% of the sum claimed will be given
and there is also optional coverage for
personal accident in which there will be
accidental death cover, permanent total
disability cover, permanent partial
disability cover and there is
also a special feature in the name of optional coverage for cancer restore
and no survival period, this is a very
amazing thing that whenever any critical
illness is diagnosed then even if the same day is missed
then also you will get the lump sum money for the critical illness.  A
day survival period is required in most policies.
In many companies, 30 days survival is
mandatory.  This means that
after suffering a critical illness, it is necessary to survive for seven days
or 30 days.  Otherwise
companies do not give claims.  But
this Crisis Shield plan of ICC LBA
comes with Zero Day Survival that means
you will get the money only if there is a critical diagnosis.  This
power will be given to you only by IC Labard and
whenever you take a new policy, there is an
initial waiting period of 90 days which
you have to keep in mind.  Who can take this policy
?  Talking about the eligibility criteria,
any person between 18 years to 65 years can
take this policy.  And here
if you take a loan up to Rs 20 lakh then there is no
medical test or any basic
requirement or any financial requirement.
This way you get the policy
without financial underwriting.  And here the
minimum sum assured is Rs 5 lakh and the maximum sum
assured you can take is up to Rs 40 lakh.  If
you are taking insurance of Rs 40 lakh, then you should
understand that in comprehensive insurance,
that insurance of Rs 1 crore will work for you
because Rs 40 lakh will work differently for every celebrity.  The
five celebrities I told you about, the five criticalities,
working for Rs 40 lakh each will work for all of them.
You will rarely find such a plan in the industry
and the policy can be taken for one year or
three years together which will be
amazing for you.  Let me talk about
what will be covered under the main five major critical illnesses.
What will be covered major and what will be covered minor.  So
number one, which I told you about, cancer,
cancer and blood disorders.  This
is a major critical illness.  Under this,
if something is diagnosed like cancer
of specified severity, major cancer will be
diagnosed.  If you have aplastic anemia, you will
need a bone marrow transplant. If
you have primary microbiosis, then it will be
counted as major. What will happen in minor? Early
stage cancer and carcinoma in situ will be
counted as minor. Major illnesses in heart and blood
vessels will include Takaso
arteritis and Eilers syndromes and
mycological
infection. First heart attack of specified
severity. Open heart replacement or repair
of heart valves. Surgery of aorta.
Refractory heart failure. Open chest
CABG. Cardiopathy. Cardiopathy of
specified severity and primary
pulmonary hypertension or infection.
Infectious endocrine disease. This is a major illness. If I
talk about minor illnesses in heart and blood vessels, then it is pulmonary artery. Cardiac
aneurysm with surgical
intervention. Complete heart block of third
degree. Angioplasty.
Minimally invasive surgery of aorta.
Moderate severe cardiopathy.
Periectomy. Other serious cardiectomy. Insertion of
a permanent cardiac or balloon.
Valvotomy and pulmonary immobilization will be
in your minor critical illnesses. Let me talk about
another major illness in the list of critical illnesses,
which is called major organs.
What will be covered in major organs?
Systemic Lupus
erythematosus Arthritis
Myasthenia Gravis Kidney Failure
Good Luck Syndrome with Lung and Renal
Involvement
Syndrome End Stage Lung Failure Malignant
Medullary
Cystic Kidney Disease End Stage Liver Disease
Severe Crohn's Disease Chronic Replastic
Pancreatitis Major Hormonal
Transplant Severe
Ulcerative Colitis These are your major illnesses
which will be covered in your critical illness.   If I
talk about minors then Severe
Acquired of Secondary Pulmonary PAP Moderate
Severe Kidney Disease Portal Vein Thrombosis
Moderately Chron's Disease Small bowel
transplant Surgical removal of one kidney
Intestinal gangrene Surgical removal of one
lung You will find all these names in the policy Let me
talk about minor and major.
In nervous system what will be the major system major diseases
Stroke Resulting in Permanent
Syndrome Motor Neuron Disease with Permanent
Syndrome Parkinson's Disease Alzheimer's Disease
Multiple Cirrhosis Muscular Dystrophy
Aplastic Syndrome These are all the names which
you will find properly in major surgery 92 types
are also critical and under minor diseases
Loss of heart of one ear Dissolution of
nerve roots of brachial plexus Apic
sclerosis Loss of eye of one eye These will be
under your minor diseases in which you will get 25%.  Let me
talk about what is Major Illness Other
Disease?  So what will be the third degree
Bs Pikomi Pikoma Netizing
Facilities minor in the major?
Elephantiasis
Optic
Nephropathy Wilson's Disease Like these will be
minor diseases of your other senses.  So friends,
I was able to explain to you that critical
illness is very important for you.  Friends,
understand that even those who have health
insurance, their health insurance is
not sufficient because
in case of critical illness, the treatment takes a long time and the
OPD treatment lasts for a long time.
Hospitalization is rare
but before that, the financial situation of the household
and many other expenses are covered by the critical illness lump
sum.  Let me
tell you the difference, health insurance is an
indemnity policy.  The
critical illness is a benefit policy.
In benefit policies, the
entire amount is transferred only after the disease is diagnosed. If a major
illness is diagnosed, then
if you have taken insurance of Rs 40 lakh, then the
company transfers Rs 40 lakh to your account.  In case of
minor illness,
25% of Rs 40 lakh i.e. Rs 1 lakh is transferred to your account.
But if you
cover critical illness through health insurance, then you will never
get any claim from health insurance until you are admitted.  So in that case you will suffer.  You will have to
spend money from your pocket.
Health insurance works only when you are admitted.
Therefore, I would request all of you to
definitely take critical insurance policies for yourself
and for this we provide this policy all over India.  I
hope
you have understood this content and its working.
Hello your friend Yogendra
Verma Insurance Expert.  Thank you.  Thank
you so much.